# **ALEXANDER GRABOWSKI**

## CONTACT

- https://xangrab.com/
- https://github.com/XanGrab/
- nttps://xangrab.itch.io/

### **PROFILE**

I have been professionally developing games for the last two years, and recreationally my entire life. I am proficient in a diverse range of full-stack toolchains targeting game and web development. I can frequently be found in international fan games, hackathons, and game jams, expressing my passion for applied learning games and FOSS. I developed a sense of leadership early, achieving the rank of Eagle Scout, and continued developing my leadership skills guiding competitive e-sports teams to compete at the national level. I am a lifelong, self-driven learner and problem solver.

#### **SKILLS**

- · Game Engines
  - Unity
  - Godot
  - Phaser
- Graphics Libraries
  - Pixi.js
  - HLSL (Unity)
  - GLSL (Three.js)
- · Programming Languages
  - o **C++**
  - o C#
  - TypeScript
- · Web Development Tools
  - Node.js
  - Vite
  - Webpack
- DevOps & Services
  - Github Actions
  - Docker
  - o Firebase BaaS
- · Digital Illustration & Wireframing
  - o Figma
  - Illustator
  - Photoshop

# **EXPERIENCE**

**Gameplay Programmer** at *Field Day Learning Games* **2022.01–2023.05** https://fielddaylab.wisc.edu/

Developer and junior designer on multiple projects including *Wake: Tales* from the Aqualab, client-side API for *Open Game Data*, and samller browser-based HTML5 games

# **Head Programming Instructor** at Code Ninjas

2020.10-2022.12

https://codeninjas.com/

Developed programming curriculum for kids of various backgrounds in the K-12 age range spanning JavaScript, MakeCode Arcade, Roblox Studio, and the Unity game engine

## Youth Esports Coach at XP League

2020.10-2022.12

https://www.xpleague.com/

Certified youth eSports coach through the Positive Coaching Alliance. Led the Sun Prairie league's Fortnite team to compete at the North American Finals 2022

# **PROJECTS**

## MOTHER<sup>2</sup>.

Unattached 2021-pres.

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zWeF1jRstLk

Released in 1994 as MOTHER 2 in Japan and as EarthBound in the west, MOTHER<sup>2</sup> is a full-length ground-up reimagining of the game by fans for fans.

- $\diamond$  Designed and developed a multitude of features for the project contributing to over 35% of the entire codebase
- Conducted playtester surveys and interviews to inform design of new features

WAKE: TALES FROM THE AQUALAB.

Field Day Learning Games

2022-2023

https://fielddaylab.wisc.edu/play/wake/

An oceanography game targeting Chromebooks in middle school classrooms helping students learn scientific experimentation, modeling, and argumentation.

- ♦ Designed pivotal story and level layout elements of the introductory sequence for the game
- ♦ Brought gameplay systems to life in Unity, implementing user interfaces for the game's Shop, Observation Tanks, and Modeling
- $\diamond$  Used in-house scripting tools to implement over seventy-five percent of the quests in the game

UNANNOUNCED HTML5 BROWSER GAMES.

Field Day Learning Games

2023

https://github.com/opengamedata/opengamedata-js-log/

Point-and-click, browser-based games targeting mobile tablets and other handheld devices.

- ♦ Built data analytics and logging tools for real-time data collection with Firebase in collaboration with the Open Game Data project
- ♦ Developed the game's dialogue system building text-parsing tooling which extended scripts written in YarnSpinner
- ♦ Adapted the game's graphics to make use of both WebGL and Canvas rendering styles to meet different tablet and mobile limitations

# **EDUCATION**

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGN CAPSTONE CERTIFICATE

University of Wisconsin—Madison

2023-pres.

BACHELOR OF ARTS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE University of Wisconsin—Madison

2019-2023

- Certification (Minor) in Game Design
- Certification in Digital Art
- Certification in Professional Japanese Communication